<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">SwipeViewWithTabs</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="YourText">
        <b>Declaration of Faith</b>
        \n\n     The Declaration of Faith is the public confession of the faith that is professed by the Iglesia Filipina Independiente. It declares belief in the Triune God and the Catholic and Apostolic character of the Church. The Declaration of Faith, with the Articles of Religion, was established by the Church in the 1947 General Assembly.

        \n\n\n<b>The Holy Trinity</b>
        \n\n     One God, true and living, of infinite power, wisdom and goodness; the Maker and Preserver of all things visible and invisible. And that in the unity of this Godhead there be three Persons, of one substance, power and eternity: the Father who is made of none, neither created nor begotten; the Son who is of the Father alone, not made nor created, but begotten, the Holy Ghost who is of the Father and the Son, neither made, nor created, nor begotten, but proceeding.

        \n\n\n<b>Jesus Christ, the only-begotten Son of God</b>
        \n\n     Jesus Christ, the only-begotten Son of God, the second Person of the Trinity, very and eternal God, of one substance with the Father, took man’s nature in the womb of the Blessed Virgin, after she had conceived by the Holy Ghost. He suffered under Pontius Pilate, was crucified, died and was buried. He descended into hell. The third day he rose again from the dead, He ascended into Heaven, and sitteth at the right hand of God the Father Almighty; from thence He shall come to judge both the living and the dead.

        \n\n\n<b>The Holy Spirit</b>
        \n\n     The Holy Spirit, the Lord and Giver of life, Who proceedeth from the Father and the Son: Who with the Father and the Son together we worship and glorify.

        \n\n\n<b>One Catholic and Apostolic Church</b>
        \n\n     The Church, Holy, Catholic and Apostolic, which is the Body of Christ, founded by Christ for the redemption and sanctification of mankind, and to which Church He gave power and authority to preach His Gospel to the whole world under the guidance of His Holy Spirit.
    </string>
</resources>
